So we just met, so I'll ask for
permission.
Can we call you Dewey? You can. Okay.
Yep. The nickname, explain. Where's
what's the backstory?
>> So we had a lot of neighbor kids growing
up that couldn't, you know, can't say
their Rs and Drew
was basically the name and then Drew
became Dew and then the rest is history.
So it's been Dewey for as long as I can
remember.
Okay.
>> Ever since the school yard.
>> I mean we're talking
>> Oh yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> 4 years old. Okay.
>> And then So basically the only people
that call me Andrew now is my girlfriend
or my mom when they're
pissed at me.
>> And that's where you got when you get
the full name
>> All right. Andrew Mercer Wingard, you
know. [laughter] So Well then
>> Other than that it's Dewey. There's also
Morris the Blade an alter ego, but we'll
get to that a little bit later. Um how
different is Arizona? Seven year all
seven years of your NFL career in
Jacksonville this has got to represent
quite a change, right? Yeah. Um
it was a great run in Jacksonville. I
was obviously undrafted and you know,
made the team and the rest is history.
So just to be here getting a chance to
play for another team in year eight is
just a blessing. It's unbelievable and
it's everything I've wanted um in terms
of being successful in the league, but
you know, now I'm only an hour and 20
minute flight from my hometown in Denver
and obviously I'm familiar with Arizona.
I haven't played a lot of golf here and
stuff. So uh it's awesome. I I can't
wait for the you know, for it all to
start up and and get out here. What was
the free agency process like for you
this time around?
It was a lot I had a lot more interest
this time around, you know, 20 20 22 was
my my first go at it and that went
pretty smoothly because Jacksonville
resigned me. So it wasn't, you know,
hitting the I I was signed before free
agency even opened, but this one I had a
lot more interest in terms of, you know,
from a bunch of teams and I'm playing
defense now and but Arizona was the
first one that right when it opened they
called me and they're like we want you.
So
it feels good to be wanted and and and
um it was stressful obviously cuz you
know, where am I going to be? How's this
going to work? This and that, but you
know, if you're testing free agency and
you're getting offers that mean that
means you've done something right and
you've had success. So that makes me
feel good about my body of work and now
it's just about getting settled in in a
new place and kind of
taking a little bit of a deep breath and
and getting going. So How much do you
think the game here influenced the
Cardinals decision makers? Like what you
put on that field put on film? Do you
think maybe that peaked their interest?
Maybe, who knows? Um
it was a great game. I had great play
there at the end, but um showing off the
range. So maybe maybe Mr. Austin Fort
saw that and was like I want that
long-haired white guy on my team. He
seems to be smart and know what he's
doing. So
You know, I I know
when I'm the sideline reporter. We got
down there, right? So I'm seeing Jackson
we don't see Jacksonville very often,
right? And I'm like wait a minute.
That's not Gardeck unless he lost 40 lb.
But there was sort of but with the hair
and everything. How often did when
Gardeck showed up did they did you guys
get confused? Well, we didn't get we
didn't get confused, but we like looked
at each other and we were like
>> [laughter]
>> you're my kind of guy.
That's good. So I loved playing with
Dennis. I mean he was he was he was
awesome and you'll find that I'm a
similar uh
I don't really know the kin. We you
know, long hair, fly around, go be a bit
of a psycho on the field and you know,
play your ass off. So um
Yeah. Well, that's how he forged his
seven year NFL career here. He was
undrafted as well.
>> Yep.
>> From a tiny school. Yeah, no. And he
actually I I knew of him cuz he went to
Sioux Falls and one of my buddies went
there and you know, a D2 guy making a
name for himself and getting paid only
fired me up even more. So it was great
to meet him and play with him for a
season. It's going to suck not being his
teammate anymore cuz I just love the guy
himself, but um I'll I'll bring a
similar sort of energy and and stuff to
the field that he brought here. Paul
brought it up. You brought up as well
being undrafted. So your journey now
going into year eight. Can you flashback
to when you were at Wyoming to think,
okay, I'm closing in now on a potential
decade career in the NFL and how you've
been able to not only survive, but
thrive in this league? Yeah. And I've
I've told people this a lot. Going
undrafted was probably the best thing
that ever happened to me because I
remember going into my senior year at
Wyoming and you know,
Kiper's saying this and Che saying that
and I'm like, oh, I'm the greatest thing
ever. I'm going to get drafted and blah
blah blah and then boom. It's like, oh.
So my senior year I was slacking off I I
was
reality check. It was a great reality
check for me and um
it lit a fire in me. It got that dog
back in me and that's kind of who I was.
I was a two-star recruit out of high
school. Wyoming was my only FBS offer.
So
going undrafted really kind of rekindled
those things within me and I was like,
I'm going to make the 53 and I'm never
going to look back and then I did and
you know, I thankfully, you know,
put into the game, you know, a lot of
guys kind of just go around unconscious
and just play and don't really try to
elevate themselves mentally and that's
kind of been my my biggest thing closing
in on a decade career is the mental side
has really pushed me and that's what
I've really focused on and it's helped
me a ton and
um I'm just thankful like I said going
undrafted to to get that fire within me
to do all those little things that I did
to get myself here. I wouldn't have been
able to if I hadn't have done those. So
um it's just a blessing and I kind of am
even more motivated now than I ever have
been. So
You know, as an organization it's been
more than a century of Cardinals
football in the last 50 years. I mean
think of some of the safeties that have
come through. Hall of Famer Adrian
Wilson, Adrian Wilson five-time Pro
Bowler, Tyrann Mathieu got his start
here and all pro. Obviously Budda Baker,
you know, all have their own like
distinct styles to every one of those
guys.
>> Right. For those who haven't seen you
play, how how would you describe your
style as a safety?
>> Yeah, I would say it's it's rugged. Um I
love to play kind of old school, do your
job, but once you arrive do it violently
and do it psychotically kind of if you
if you will. So that's kind of going to
be my it'll probably be similar to
Budda. Just absolutely fly around, go
1,000 miles an hour and see what
happens. So but with a little bit of
discipline there to do your job. So
um hopefully they see that style and
I've definitely tried to expand my game
as as my career has gone on to you know,
be more finesse and cover well and and
you know,
break on the ball with range in the
deep, you know, deep half, deep middle.
So um continuing to evolve and hopefully
I can be a do-it-all guy. You know,
Budda calls it running into the
darkness.
>> Mhm. Are you born with that or is that
something maybe your desperation not
getting drafted? I mean is that is that
ingrained in you at some point or you
just think that's intrinsic? You know,
it's it's a good question because I
remember when I first started playing
football I was so scared. Like I in
little league and in middle school like
I was like didn't want to get hit. And
then for whatever reason,
you know, my dad one day in in little
league football he's like he's like, you
know, be the F'ing hammer not the F'ing
nail, you know? And I was like, okay.
And then there was one I remember one
day it hit me in in like middle school
practice. I finally just did you know,
didn't tense up and
I actually went
and I was like, holy cow. That went
that didn't hurt. I'm fine now and then
boom. From from then on it's like
go in, go 1,000 miles an hour, be the
hammer not the nail. So whether it's
intrinsic, whether it's learned, I don't
know, but
thankfully I got it somehow some way. So
Watching from afar, what do you know
about Budda the player and you'll
obviously get to know about him as a
person, but now as a teammate and
potentially sharing the secondary with
him.
>> Right. Yeah, and he's he's just a beast,
you know what I mean? And I've seen the
interview of him, you know, where he's
crying and he's like I'm sick of losing
and stuff and that that's the one that
hits home the most as a guy that hates
to hates to lose more than he loves to
win. So
um
I'm just excited to learn from a guy. I
I I don't even know what year he's in,
10 or 11 maybe, but one of the highest
paid safeties and so he's a a guy you're
I'm endlessly going to keep my eye on
and and learn from and maybe I can give
him a few tips here and there, but it's
going to be fun and you know, with the
young guy uh uh Dayvion. He he messaged
me right when I got signed. So
um
it's just cool. It's like, okay, let's
work, you know what I mean? So I'm
excited to get in with these guys and
craft and hopefully turn this place
around. We saw New England go [snorts]
from four wins to 14 wins in the Super
Bowl, right?
>> Mhm. Jacksonville obviously a miraculous
turnaround. Yep. Is there anything you
can share with this team coming off last
year this year?
>> Yeah, I mean I I've done that twice in
Jacksonville where you come off a
you know, three or four win year and and
then in 22 we go nine and eight, win the
division and you know, win a playoff
game and then again four and 13 in 2024
in Jacksonville and then turn around 13
and four.
Um
so
I've watched this team enough and having
played against them last year the team
is good enough.
And I think that was what was big with
Jacksonville last year is
we had a lot of the group left from
those playoff teams. We just needed the
right direction and we needed, you know,
to come together and really, you know,
buy in. And so I think that's
you know, you bring in coach LaFleur.
You got a bunch of guys that have been
here and Budda and
Jacoby, all the you know, Trey, all
those guys. So if you can really, you
know,
have those guys that have been through
stuff together and it brings the locker
room together and then they buy into the
coaching staff.
It's a pretty good ingredient uh for
success. So hopefully that can happen
here, but I would say that's the
the thing that can really put this team
over the top is when the guys come
together and then you get a new coach
who knows what he's doing and it just
kind of blooms. So, um but like I said,
the talent the talent issue is not an
issue on this team. I remember last year
coming into the game we played, I was
like, this is going to be our hardest
game of the year because
you look at the team team's record and
everyone's going to go, okay, this is
going to be an easy win. Like, no. No.
This is a very talented team and um so
combine that with leadership, you never
know what can happen. You sound like you
have a similar mindset to a lot of the
players already here.
Transitioning though from a team in
Jacksonville that you spent your entire
career now coming here,
do you think it's going to be much of a
transition or you can come right in and
really assimilate with everyone else?
Yeah, I think the when guys get in the
league, I think it it's not like a
all I'm going to have a hard time blend
it, you know, the NFL
NFL players in general, the com- the
camaraderie between NFL players is
really good. So, I don't think that's
going to be an issue, but obviously
there's going to be a lot of guys here,
you know, with coach Rallis coming back
that know the system. So, I think
that'll be my first sort of
objective is learning the system. So,
I'll definitely be behind from that
sense, but other than that, I've done
this before, you know. I I've turned
around, you know, turned around
Jacksonville twice. So, I'm I'm no
I'm not new to, you know, having success
after a bad year. So, I think that can
only help and I can obviously bring some
light, you know, to guys that maybe have
questions or this or that and how did
you do this? How did you do that? So,
I'm hopefully just trying to add to the
to the pot of stew and add my
ingredient. All right. Now, when you
signed on the line that is dotted, did
you sign Andrew? Did you sign Dewey? Or
did you sign Morris the Blade? Well, I
wish I could have signed Morris the
Blade, but I technically had to go with
the government name, but yeah, no.
Hopefully Morris the Blade will come
I I would have liked to have seen him a
little more this past year. Um I need to
definitely go back to my roots of
getting into getting into my flow state
a little better more more often, I guess
I should say cuz there were spurts of
it, but you know, when I really get
going I and I really, you know, turn
that alter ego on and
uh
it can get fun. It can get fun quick.
So.
>> So, it's like reaching the zone? Yeah,
you know, it's kind of Kobe's Mamba, you
know. Um
it's just you turn into someone new and
you know, I'm sure you guys in whatever
your background you you've just had
those days, you know, where you you just
got your stuff working and it's so easy
um and I'm sure
you've maybe coined an alter ego, maybe,
but that's just kind of how it is. When
you when you when you before you turn on
the microphone, you tend to change a
little bit
>> Well, I try with a poly pigskin, you
know, I try with poly pigskin. Not
doesn't get a lot of traction. I don't
get respected as such, but you know, I I
go down swinging, you know, we'll see.
We'll see. Yeah. I mean,
let me ask you this. Um in terms of your
game, is there an underrated part of
your game? Is there something like
you're coming in and you're like, you
know, people maybe this doesn't show up
in all the scouting reports?
Well, at you know, my whole career in
Jacksonville everyone oh, he's this
white guy, he's a special teamer, he's a
backup depth player. Yeah, get get out
of here. Like, I'm a starter in this
league. Like, I've played a lot of
football in this league and I've made a
lot of plays and you know, last year
I've really only had two chances that a
coaching staff has gone, okay, like
like we trust you and and you're the guy
and I've balled out every time I've had
that opportunity. So, I I would say
there's underrated parts of my game,
like just watch the tape. Like, my
coverage my coverage last year was
great.
My over the top coverage was great. So,
I think the underrated parts that I I
wouldn't consider underrated about
myself because I'm confident in myself
would just be
coverage ability and and speed and and
over the top range. So, I'm going to do
all those things and I've
finally I've got the chance and last
year I got the chance to do it. So, I'm
just going to continue to do those
things and and continue to, you know,
make my game whole.
Um you know, coming down in the box,
covering tight ends, run fits, I can do
that in my sleep. So, I've definitely
worked on it and now I'm confident in
being in the whole the whole game.
Coverage, run stopping, speed, tackling,
all that. So, I I can do it all. 16
starts last season for Jacksonville.
Welcome aboard. Mhm. Dewey. Yes, sir.
>> We're on a first name basis, nickname
basis here. Yes, sir. So, welcome in and
uh look forward to getting to know you
more, but excited to have you in the
building.
>> Absolutely. Thank you guys. Appreciate
it.